Finding Aid for Robin B. Wright papers, 1970-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Robin B. Wright papers 1970-1997
Wright, Robin B., 1948-
4 linear feet
89461 Aa 2
Correspondent for The Christian Science Monitor, The Washington Post, CBS News, and other news organizations; author of books on Middle Eastern politics. Scrapbooks and copies of articles largely concerning African and Middle Eastern politics; and scattered correspondence and biographical material.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. L. Hart Wright (donor no. 6260 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Robin Wright is a newspaper and television news correspondent, expert in foreign affairs and diplomacy, especially relating to the Middle East. At various times, she has reported for The Washington Post, the Los Angeles Times, The Sunday Times of London, CBS News and The Christian Science Monitor. She has also written for The New Yorker, The Atlantic Monthly, Foreign Affairs, Foreign Policy, The New York Times, The Times (London), The Guardian (London), The International Herald Tribune and many others. She has appeared as guest on network news programs and is a regular panelist on Meet the Press. She is currently (2007) diplomatic correspondent for T he Washington Post.
Wright has authored several books on the Middle East and Africa, and has taught and lectured on foreign affairs topics. She was the recipient of numerous awards, including a John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation grant.
The Wright collection is an accumulation of articles and scrapbooks, compiled by Robin Wright's mother, Mrs. L. Hart Wright. The collection also contains a scattering of correspondence, photographs, and biographical information.
Subjects:
Africa--Politics and government--1960-; Journalists--United States.; Middle East--Politics and government--1945-
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Wright, Robin B., 1948-
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Personal
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Book: Sacred Rage, by Robin Wright (Box 1)
    (include newspaper reviews of the book)
  - Book: In the Name of God, by Robin Wright (Box 1)
- Articles
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1970 (Box 1)
  - 1971 (Box 1)
  - 1972 (Box 1)
  - 1973 (Box 1)
  - 1974 (Box 1)
  - 1974 (Trans-Africa Trek) (Box 1)
  - 1975 (Box 1)
  - 1975-1976 (Alicia Patterson Foundation Award articles) (Box 1)
  - January-March 1976 (Box 1)
  - April-June 1976 (Box 1)
  - July-September 1976 (Box 1)
  - October-December 1976 (Box 1)
  - 1977 (Box 1)
  - 1978 (Box 1)
  - 1979 (Box 1)
  - 1981 (Box 1)
  - January-July 1982 (Box 1)
  - August-December 1982 (Box 1)
  - 1983 (Box 1)
  - 1986 (Box 1)
  - 1987 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks
  - 1976, 2 volumes (Box 1)
    (the volumes include clippings, miscellaneous notes and correspondence, 1974-1976)
  - 1986-1991 (Box 2)
  - 1991-1994 (Box 3)
  - 1995-1997 (Box 4)